欢迎来到关于 CSS 的第一讲。
Welcome to the first lecture about CSS.
所以就像我们在 HTML 基础部分所做的那样，
So just like we did in the HTML fundamental section,
在本节中，我们还将首先查看
in this section we will also start by looking
CSS实际上是什么，
at what CSS actually is,
我们将学习一些常用术语，
and we will learn some common terminology,
这样你就永远知道我在说什么
so that you always know what I'm talking about
当我提到不同的 CSS 代码时。
when I refer to different pieces of the CSS code.
所以首先，
So first of all,
CSS 代表层叠样式表。
CSS stands for Cascading Style Sheets.
就像 HTML 一样，
And just like HTML,
CSS 也是 Web 的核心技术之一。
CSS is also one of the core technologies of the web.
现在记住我们使用 HTML
Now remember that we use HTML
基本上描述页面的内容。
to basically describe the content of a page.
而另一方面，
And on the other hand,
我们使用 CSS 来描述视觉风格
we use CSS to describe the visual style
和内容的呈现
and the presentation of the content
我们之前使用 HTML 编写的。
that we previously wrote using HTML.
所以 CSS 和 HTML 非常紧密地结合在一起。
So CSS and HTML work very closely together.
事实上，在这里，你可以看到一个网页，
And in fact, down here, you can see a webpage,
这实际上是我们将构建的项目
which is actually the project that we will build
在课程的后期。
later in the course.
所以在左边你只有内容。
So in the left side you have just the content.
所以只是HTML。
So just the HTML.
然后在右边，
And then on the right side,
你有完全相同的 HTML 代码，但有很多 CSS。
you have the exact same HTML code, but with a lot of CSS.
这样 CSS 就描述了视觉风格
And so that CSS describes the visual style
以及整个内容的基本布局。
and also the layout basically of that whole content.
现在，正如你已经知道的，
Now, as you already know,
HTML由一堆不同的元素组成
HTML consists of a bunch of different elements
我们可以用来描述内容。
that we can use to describe the content.
同样，CSS 与此类似，
And so again, CSS is similar to that,
因为 CSS 包含无数的属性
because CSS consists of countless properties
然后我们的开发人员可以使用它来格式化内容。
that we developers can then use to format the content.
这些属性允许我们格式化不同的东西
And these properties allow us to format different things
关于字体，文本，一般间距，
about a font, the text, the general spacing,
页面布局等等。
a layout of the page and so on and so forth.
真的有很多不同的属性。
There is really lots of different properties.
当然，您无需熟记于心。
And of course you don't need to know all of them by heart.
没有必要这样做。
There's just no need for that.
你学习这些属性的方式
The way that you learn these properties
是你一遍又一遍地使用最重要的，
is that you use the most important ones over and over again,
在某一时刻，它会变得非常直观。
and at one point it will then become very intuitive.
好的，这就是 CSS 的全部意义所在。
Okay, so this is what CSS is all about.
所以现在让我们来看一段实际的 CSS 代码。
So let's now take a look at an actual piece of CSS code.
这就是典型的一小段 CSS
So this is what a typical small piece of CSS
可能看起来像。
might look like.
它总是以选择器开头。
And it always starts with a selector.
例如，
So for example,
如果我们想为页面上的所有 h1 元素设置样式，
if we want to style all the h1 elements on the page,
我们需要在 CSS 中选择它，
we need to select it in CSS,
然后我们可以对其应用一些样式。
and then we can apply some styles to it.
所以这些风格中的每一种，我们都可以称之为声明。
And so each of these styles, we can call it a declaration.
例如，这里我们将字体大小设置为 20 像素。
So for example, here we set the font size to 20 pixels.
因此字体大小称为属性。
And so that font size is called the property.
而 20 像素是我们声明的值
And the 20 pixels is the value that we declare
对于该字体大小属性。
for that font size property.
所以财产和价值一起是一个声明。
And so property and value together is a declaration.
我们也可以更随意地称其为风格。
And we can also, more casually, call that a style.
然后所有这些声明，或样式一起，
Then all of these declarations, or styles together,
组成声明块。
make up the declaration block.
所以我们在选择器后面有这些花括号，
So we have these curly braces after the selector,
所以在声明块里面
and so inside of the declaration block
去所有不同的声明。
go all the different declarations.
所以我们所有的风格。
So all our styles.
而这一切加在一起，
And all this together,
所以基本上选择器加上声明块
so basically the selector plus the declaration block
是我们c都是 CSS 规则。
is what we call a CSS rule.
所以这意味着，最终我们的 CSS 代码
And so what this means, is that in the end our CSS code
会有很多不同的CSS规则，一个接一个，
will be a lot of different CSS rules, one after another,
我们选择所有元素的地方
where we select all of our elements
并以我们想要的任何方式设计它们。
and style them in any way that we want.
好的。
Okay.
这正是我们将开始做的事情
And so that is exactly what we will start doing
在下一个视频中。
in the next video.
所以我们现在就去那里。
So let's go there right now.